As we continue to lay the groundwork for our marketing analytics,
我们继续讲市场分析的一些基础知识
I want to revisit the topic of setting our business objectives.
我想详细讲下业务目标的设定
I think it's important that we go a little deeper into what makes up our goals.
详细了解业务目标的组成 还是很重要的
Now, you might also hear these interchangeably
业务目标 business goals 也称为 市场目标 marketing goals
referred to as business goals or marketing goals,
两个术语经常换着用
and these are terms that all mean the same thing.
是一个意思
Now your business objectives are the measurable targets of what you want to achieve,
业务目标应该是你想取得的成绩的一个可衡量的目标
and all business objectives should follow the SMART goal format.
所有业务目标都应该遵循 SMART 准则
SMART stands for Specific,
SMART 的意思是： Specific(具体)
Measurable, Achievable, Relevant, and Time-Bound.
Measurable(可衡量) Achievable(可达到的) Relevant(相关性) 以及 Time-Bound (时效性)
As a grocery store, I might say that my objective is to sell
比如一家超市 它的目标可能是尽可能地卖更多的东西
as much product as I can at the highest profit margin that I can.
最大限度地提高毛利率
But that's actually a very broad view.
但是这个目标太笼统了
We need to really frame this objective in the context of SMART.
我们应该根据 SMART 准则重新制定目标
Instead, we'd be better off saying,
比如
generate $50,000 in revenue for the month of March.
在 3 月份达到 5 万美元的收入
It's specific because we're sticking to just revenue,
这个就很具体的 具体到收入
we're not layering in other pieces.
而不是其他指标
It's measurable because there is a metric there, $50,000.
这个目标也是可衡量的 要达到 5 万美元
Now it's achievable, and this is all based on
至于可不可以达到
how realistic this will be for your business.
要看这个目标对于你的业务来说是否是现实的
Stretched goals are great but if the store is only doing $10,000 a month on average,
有理想是好的 但是如果你的超市一个月基本上就收入 1 万美元
asking for a $40,000 improvement in one month might not really be achievable.
在一个月内提升 4 万美元 基本就不可能了
In this case, we'll assume that it is achievable.
我们目前先假设这个目标是可实现的
Now it's relevant and it's time-bound because
显然 这个目标与业务是相关的 同时也是有时效性的
we're measuring it in the context of one quarter.
因为我们是对它有一个月的要求
Now this is a pretty broad objective.
这个目标其实还是有点笼统
So you might actually take this and break it down into
所以我们其实可以继续细分成
individual initiatives that help you realize that goal.
不同的小目标 来帮助我们更好地达到
Now oftentimes, we break these objectives into key performance indicators,
通常 目标　(objectives) 可以细分成 关键绩效指标 KPI－key performance indicators
and we'll talk more on that later.
后续我们会详细说
But ultimately, let's say for the grocery store that one of
比如　在超市的例子里　一个小目标就可以是
these smaller items is going to be boosting sales of soda,
提高苏打水的销量
which is a high-margin product.
因为苏打水的毛利率很高
Or perhaps, in order to achieve that 50,000 revenue goal,
或者　为了达到 5 万美元的目标
we really need to increase the efficiency of our ads,
我们需要提高广告的效益
which will save us money,
在带来同等收益的情况下
but try to still bring in that same amount of revenue.
减少广告开支
As you look at your analytics project,
综上 做分析项目的时候 00:02:12,514 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 记得遵循 SMART 原则